[
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> Which one of the following is not a viral disease?</H3>",
        "options": ["Dengue", "AIDS", "Typhoid", "Influenza"],
        "correctAnswer": 2
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> Which one of the following is not a bacterial disease?</H3>",
        "options": ["Cholera", "Tuberculosis", "Anthrax", "Influenza"],
        "correctAnswer": 3
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> Which one of the following disease is not transmitted by mosquito?</H3>",
        "options": ["Brain fever", "Malaria", "Typhoid", "Dengue"],
        "correctAnswer": 2
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> Which one of the following disease is caused by bacteria?</H3>",
        "options": ["Typhoid", "Anthrax", "Tuberculosis", "Malaria"],
        "correctAnswer": 3
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> Which one of the following diseases is caused by protozoans?</H3>",
        "options": ["Malaria", "Influenza", "AIDS", "Cholera"],
        "correctAnswer": 0
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> Which one of the following has a long term effect on the health of an individual?</H3>",
        "options": ["Common cold", "Chicken pox", "Chewing tobacco", "Stress"],
        "correctAnswer": 2
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> Which of the following can make you ill if you come in contact with an infected person?</H3>",
        "options": ["High blood pressure", "Genetic abnormalities", "Sneezing", "Blood cancer"],
        "correctAnswer": 2
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> AIDS cannot be transmitted by</H3>",
        "options": ["sexual contact", "hugs", "breast feeding", "blood transfusion"],
        "correctAnswer": 1
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> Making anti-viral drugs is more difficult than making anti-bacterial medicines because</H3>",
        "options": ["viruses make use of host machinery", "viruses are on the border line of living and non-living",
                    "viruses have very few biochemical mechanisms of their own", "viruses have a protein coat"],
        "correctAnswer": 2
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> Which one of the following causes kala-azar?</H3>",
        "options": ["Ascaris", "Trypanosoma", "Leishmania", "Bacteria"],
        "correctAnswer": 2
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> If you live in a overcrowded and poorly ventilated house, it is possible that you may suffer from which of the following diseases</H3>",
        "options": ["Cancer", "AIDS", "Air borne diseases", "Cholera"],
        "correctAnswer": 2
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> Which disease is not transmitted by mosquitoes?</H3>",
        "options": ["Dengue", "Malaria", "Brain fever or encephalitis", "Pneumonia"],
        "correctAnswer": 3
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> Which one of the following is not important for individual health?</H3>",
        "options": ["Living in clean space", "Good economic condition", "Social equality and harmony", "Living in a large and well furnished house"],
        "correctAnswer": 3
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> Choose the wrong statement</H3>",
        "options": ["High blood pressure is caused by excessive weight and lack of exercise.", "Cancers can be caused by genetic abnormalities",
                    "Peptic ulcers are caused by eating acidic food", "Acne in not caused by staphylococci"],
        "correctAnswer": 2
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> We should not allow mosquitoes to breed in our surroundings because they</H3>",
        "options": ["multiply very fast and cause pollution", "are vectors for many diseases", "bite and cause skin diseases", "are not important insects"],
        "correctAnswer": 1
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> You are aware of Polio Eradication Programme in your city. Children are vaccinated because</H3>",
        "options": ["vaccination kills the polio causing microorganisms", "prevents the entry of polio causing organism", "it creates immunity in the body", "all the above"],
        "correctAnswer": 2
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> Viruses, which cause hepatitis, are transmitted through</H3>",
        "options": ["air", "water", "food", "personal contact"],
        "correctAnswer": 1
    },
    {
        "type": "multiple-choice",
        "question": "<H3>[<I>Chapter: Why Do We Fall Ill</I>]<br> Vectors can be defined as</H3>",
        "options": ["animals carry the infecting agents from sick person to another healthy person", "microorganisms which cause many diseases",
                    "infected person", "diseased plants"],
        "correctAnswer": 0
    }
]
